This next section of the course will deal with
aggregates, summaries of numeric portions of
our data. There are several aggregates to cover,
but I will start with what is, for most, the most
common one, and that is SUM. Take a look at this
query. It just has each salesperson by name and ID
and the total for each salesperson.
I have joined the tables necessary to
get the names of the salespersons. I will
execute this query, and we see right away
a very common problem people see when
trying to run a query with aggregates,
such as this SUM aggregate we see. The error
message states that the LastName column is invalid
because it is not being used in an aggregate,
which is true, it is not being summarized,
and there is no GROUP BY clause. For aggregates
in SQL, this is the important part: The query has
to be told how to summarize the data. In this
case, is it just for each SalesPersonID? Is it
just for each last name? In reality, any column
not in an aggregate in a query like this needs to
be grouped. Thus, we need to add a GROUP BY clause
so that this query is grouped by the three columns
above the summary. Here is a real-life trick
I like to use. Notice that I have the columns
listed first and then the SUM aggregate. Doing
it this way makes it easy for me to add the words
GROUP BY and then copy and paste the columns
to be grouped here. I will execute this again,
and we see the SUM total of
sales for each salesperson.